GREG OUJFS Front End Developer

Atlanta, GA

504.220.3832

Greg@GregRoques.com

GregRoques.com

github.com/GregRoques

in linkedin.com/in/GregRoques

ABOUT ME

I am a former creative director turned software developer with more than 10 years of experience managing award-winning print and online publications. Primarily serving as an editor and art director in my previous roles, I began to witness a sharp shift from the printed page to the more modern digital canvas early in

my career. While serving as creative director for a local magazine, I took the lead in establishing the brand's digital presence. I taught myself as much as I could about UI/Ux to ensure our interface and content best suited our readership, designed initial wireframes for the site, and learned HTML/CSS and basic JavaScript to optimize layouts and functionality within our CMS applications. Thanks to these efforts in collaboration with our development team, our website would quickly become the most awarded digital publication in the city. After several years of pivoting towards digital strategy while continually learning to code, I realized my passion was to dive further into the development of the systems I was directing. I decided to fully dedicate my creative energies towards the design and development of efficient, user-focussed software solutions.

Experience

Graphic Design 10+ years (including Adobe CC programs Illustrator, Indesign, Photoshop and Premiere Pro)

Staff and Project Management 9+ years

Digital Strategy 6+ years (social media and web editorial management; use of Google and Facebook Analytics and Google Adsense and API)

HTML/CSS 5+ years JavaScript 3+ years

React, Redux, **Express and Node** 1+ years

EDUCATION

Full-Stack Development DigitalCrafts '19 ~ Atlanta, GA

Graphic Design Tulane '10 ~ New Orleans, LA

B.A., Journalism LSU '04 ~ Baton Rouge, LA

INTERESTS

Running • Obstacle Racing Photography • Music

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

Portfolio www.GregRogues.com/Portfolio

Programming Languages:

Front End: HMTL/CSS • Bootstrap • JavaScript • jQuery • Angular • React • Redux Back End: Node • Express • MySQL • MongoDB

CAREER

Freelance Front End Software Developer

June 2019 - present ~ Atlanta, GA (Remote)

• Developing a website and digital marketing strategy for an independent healthcare provider.

DigitalCrafts Developer in Residence

November 2018 - June 2019 ~ Atlanta, GA

• Completed 16-week immersive full-stack engineering program. Following my cohort, I accepted a full-time position as a Developer in Residence working with a course instructor to assist current students with projects and programming concepts.

American Red Cross Regional Marketing and Communications Manager March 2016 - November 2018 ~ New Orleans, LA

- Direct local digital media strategy and act as a media liaison and spokesperson during regional disasters, including the Louisiana August 2016 floods and the 2017 hurricane season response.
- Responsible for recruitment, training and retention of Louisiana communications volunteer staff and internship programs across the region.
- Design and teach trainings for regional staff, boards and stakeholders: skills covered included becoming a spokesperson, social media management and digital storytelling.
- Led local media team responsible for generating more than \$1.8 million in earned media value during the first six months of the 2017-2018 fiscal year.

Where Y'at Magazine Creative Director

Jan. 2010 - March 2016 ~ New Orleans, LA

- Conceptualized and assigned editorial for print and digital publications.
- Designed print and digital advertisements and editorial layouts.
- Served as the digital director, managing the website, eNewsletter and social media content creation and editorial calendar; experience using HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
- Responsible for staff recruitment, management and retention; this included leading a team of approximately 30 freelancers, interns and editorial managers.
- Led the audience development strategy rebranding the publication to target the city's young professional market. This included redesigning the print publication and overseeing the development of an upgraded website and digital presence.